says solve for x no calculator the first
step I think I want to set everything
equal to zero so I'm going to subtract
2x from both sides and add 3x squared to
both sides so on the right hand side
it's going to be equal to 0. we have X
cubed plus 3x squared minus 2X x is 0 is
1 so it's going to be minus six from
here we're going to do Factor by
grouping we're going to pull out the
common x squared for these two terms and
a common negative 2 for these two terms
and it's still equal to zero x squared
times what gives us X cubed that's x x
squared times what gives us 3x squared
that's three negative 2 times what gives
us negative 2x that's X and negative 2
times y gives us negative 6 that's
positive 3. now both of these have an X
plus 3 term so I'm going to factor that
out so I have X plus 3 times what gives
me all of this that's going to be x
squared and then X plus 3 times what
gives me all this that's minus 2. and
from here we know either X plus 3 equals
0 or x squared minus two equals 0. we'll
subtract 3 from both sides and we get x
equals negative three and for this one
we add 2 to both sides get x squared
equals two square root both sides and we
get x equals plus or minus root two and
these are the three answers for X how
exciting